<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Play by Play | kgn]]></title>
  <link href="http://kgn.github.com/blog/categories/play-by-play/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://kgn.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-03-02T16:05:48-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://kgn.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Your Name]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Play by Play: Featured by Apple]]></title>
    <link href="http://kgn.github.com/blog/2012/02/11/play-by-play-featured-by-apple/"/>
    <updated>2012-02-11T19:11:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://kgn.github.com/blog/2012/02/11/play-by-play-featured-by-apple</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This week one of my dreams came true, <a href="http://playbyplayapp.com">Play by Play</a> was featured on the <strong>New and Noteworthy</strong> section of the <strong>Mac App Store</strong>!</p>

<!-- more -->


<p><img class="center" src="http://kgn.github.com/content/playbyplay/new+noteworthy.png"></p>

<p>On monday I received an email out of the blue from Apple requesting art assets for a potential promotion. I was so excited I put together the art and sent it off the same day!</p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://kgn.github.com/content/playbyplay/promo.png"></p>

<p>Unfortunately Apple didn't use this art or make a custom App Store page, but that just leaves more to strive for for my next featured app :)</p>

<p>Besides being a great honor being featured is also great for business :) I didn't make Play by Play for the money, and it's not <em>killin it</em> by any stretch of the imagination, but I put a lot of time into this app and definitely want to see it do well. The app sold really well the first couple days, thanks in part to the amazing icon <a href="http://softfacade.com/">SoftFacade</a> created and posted on <a href="http://drbl.in/cBRY">Dribbble</a>. It dropped off after this until a review from <a href="http://mac.appstorm.net/reviews/graphics/dribbble-on-your-desktop-with-play-by-play/">Mac.AppStorm</a>. Then tapered off again and has stayed pretty constant until it was added to <em>New and Noteworthy</em>! It sold alright the first day, then doubled the second and it looks like it will sell about the same today, based on it's ranking.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://kgn.github.com/content/playbyplay/graph.png"></p>

<p>With Play by Play I put the best of what I've learned over the past couple years as I refined how I design and develop apps, and the ride has been great so far! I've made new designer and developer friends, had great interactions with users, and being recognized by Apple is the icing on the cake :)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
